Gijs Wels





05/29/1997



+31611856348



gijswels@gmail.com



Amsterdam



gijswels.github.io

Qualities

- People oriented
- ◆ Curious
- ◆ Independent
- ◆ Team player
- ◆ Solution oriented

Languages



Industrial Design Engineer

I am an industrial designer with a focus on physical products and the relationships we create between people and their world through design - the new behaviours and experiences they enable. I have a special interest in well-being, innovation, and good design, both aesthetically and practically. I learned that it is not only important to dream but also to realise. This results in a hardworking person who motivates those around him to achieve the same goals - to make things happen!

Education

MSc Integrated Product Design

May 29, 2024

TU Delft, Delft

» Product(-service) design, concept design, technical prototyping, and manufacturing. Thesis - Empowering Psychosocial Well-Being at the Workplace.

Grade - 9

BSc Industrial Design Engineering

2021

TU Delft, Delft

» Technology, bussiness, people, and design.

Minor Architecture

2019

2015

TU Delft, Delft

» House of the future, analysing global trends, and spatial design and planning.

VWO+

s.g. Spieringshoek, Schiedam

Extracurricular

Ambassadeurs van Amsterdam

09/2024 - 12/2024

De Bildung Academie, Amsterdam

Tackling a societal issue, developing a project plan in a diverse group, and running a pilot.

Summer School

07/2023 - 08/2023

Aalto University, Helsinki

» Design environments in balance with nature in an international and multidisciplinary group.

Exchange

01/2023 - 06/2023

Chalmers University, Gothenburg

» UX, form & manufacturing, manufacturing strategy, and introduction in data science & AI.

Internship

09/2020 - 02/2021

DigiNova, Delft

 $\,{}_{^{>\!\!\!\!>}}$ UX/UI, human-system interaction, and development. Applications for robots in healthcare.

Employment

Royal Ahrend

10/2023 - 05/2024

Office Furniture, Sint-Oedenrode

» Graduation project. Studying behaviour, work culture, and employee well-being (stress).

MBO Riinland

Frankeland

02/2019 - 06/2019

Secretary School, Gouda

» Teaching assistent.

08/2012 - 02/2023

Nursing Home, Schiedam

» Host. Bridge between elderly and management.

Noteworthy Achievements

Micro-Break Communication Tool

Royal Ahrend, Sint-Oedenrode

» By creating social awareness the goal is to counter the rising trend of burnout complaints.

by creating social awareness the goal is to counter the hising tiend of bullloat complaints

Natural Seating

Aalto University, Helsinki

» Seat to connect with nature; focus on functionality, minimalistic design and biodegradability.

» Seat to connect with nature, rocus on functionality, minimalistic design and biodegradability

Adjustable School Chair

Royal Ahrend, Sint-Oedenrode

» Desk chair for Dutch primary education; adjustable to all students from the age of 5 to 12.

Adaptable City Square

The Green Village, Delft

» Bachelor thesis; green solution to the urban heat island effect in the municipality of Delft.

My thesis is selected for Human Factors NL thesis award and I got selected to speak at the Vital Work-event at the High Tech Campus.

2024

2023

2021

I got selected by my faculty to participate in an international and multidisciplinary project about the use of wood in balance with nature.

High difficulty. An ergonomically almost impossible task, but I fondly look back on it. Ahrend wants to release the chair in the future.

Of all thirty participating students, my solution got selected by the organisation to continue.















nature's seat



urban oasis



Skills

3D Modelling

SolidWorks Rhinoceros Drawing

Visual Communication

Drawing Adobe Illustrator Adobe Photoshop Adobe InDesign Adobe Premiere

Digital Prototyping

Adobe Dreamweaver Android Studio Figma Axure Adobe XD Arduino & Raspberry

Physical Prototyping

Rapid Prototyping Workshop Experienced

I know my way around

HTML CSS JavaScript Python Mathlab Arduino Raspberry Pi